George Marsh

Personal Details

Nationality: British

Email: georgemarsh1809@gmail.com

WhatsApp: +44 7783 001911

Personal Statement

I'm a compassionate creative at heart with an aptitude and motivation for real-world problem-solving that has a lasting and sustainable impact. With over 5 years of experience in technology, I'm now open to new challenges where I can utilise my creativity and develop human-centric solutions. By completing my degree alongside working for my last employer, I've been able to gain real-world experience in every stage of the Software Development Lifecycle. In my last role, I worked as Lead Application Engineer on a web-based application, operating within the DevOps space. During this role, I developed an expertise in cloud deployment, utilising containerisation technologies such as Docker, and managing servers using modern and legacy cloud platforms, such as Microsoft Azure and WebLogic. I've also developed a proficiency in various coding languages over the years, such as React.js, Java and Python. Operating in remote agile teams provided me with valuable work experience in fast-paced environments where the needs of the client are continuously reviewed, and solutions are efficiently formulated. My strong sense of empathy allows me to understand the pain points of the user experience on an emotional level, and my creative approach to problem-solving allows me to think outside of the box, and ideate solutions that focus on the user.

Education

BSc (Hons) Digital and Technical Solutions (Software Engineering) (1st Class Hons), (2021 - 2023)

University of Winchester, Winchester, UK

Level 4 HNC in Software Testing, **(2019 - 2021)** *Firebrand Training, UK*

4 A-Levels, in Physics, Mathematics, Computer Science and EPQ (2017 - 2019) Queen Elizabeth's Grammar School, Kent, UK

15 GCSEs, including Mathematics, English Literature, English Language and Physics (2017)

Queen Elizabeth's Grammar School, Kent, UK

Work Experience

Software Consultant, CGI IT UK (Sept. 2019 - Jan. 2024)

- CGI's flexibility enabled me to try out various roles over the years, from tester to technical support analyst, to application and operations engineer.
- My most recent role was Lead Application Engineer on a project related to criminal justice in the UK, where I developed my skills in Linux and Windows environments, utilising modern tools like Azure and Docker.
- Specialised in the deployment process, also making use of legacy systems like WebLogic.
- Managed service and incidents using tools like ServiceNow and Jira.
- Worked on technical documentation of infrastructure and release instructions.

Customer Consultant, Carphone Warehouse (Aug. 2018 - July, 2019)

- Helped customers choose a new phone contract that was best suited to them by quickly building rapport and empathising with their needs.
- Performed tasks such as data transfers and contract renewals.

Sales Assistant, Home Bargains (Feb. 2017 - July, 2018)

- Worked as a sales assistant, building invaluable soft skills whilst learning some basic fundamentals of how the retail industry works.
- Duties included reloading stock, helping customers and serving them at the tills.

Junior Football Referee, Kent Football Association (Dec. 2015 - May, 2017)

- Completed the Kent FA's course to become a junior football referee, officiating junior football matches on weekends.
- Improved social confidence and communication skills, managing high-pressure situations.

Technical Skills Summary

- Development experience in various languages, primarily React.js, HTML/CSS,
 Python & Java
- Change management/implementation, using ServiceNow, Azure, Docker
- Wireframe and UI design for web based applications using Figma
- ❖ Incident investigation, **root cause analysis** and resolution within agile teams
- Project tracking using ticket-based tools such as Jira
- ❖ Acting as a subject matter expert within an **Agile** team
- MySQL and Postgres Databases
- WebLogic and Linux command lines

Soft Skills Summary

- ❖ High level of emotional intelligence
- Exceptional interpersonal skills, including adaptability, mediation, and all forms of communication
- Meticulous and precise attention to detail
- Excellent ability to grasp new ideas and incorporate them into current problems or connect them to related concepts
- Logical and creative approach to problem solving
- Open-minded and cognitively flexible
- ❖ Highly proficient in common Microsoft tools, such as Word and Excel
- Can work well alone or in a team

Qualifications

- ❖ AWS Cloud Practitioner (Nov. 2022)
- ❖ ISTQB Foundation (Jan, 2020)
- ❖ Full UK Driving License (Mar. 2018)
- Level 1 Table Tennis Coach (2016)
- Duke of Edinburgh's Bronze Award (2016)